export const COSTINGA2013 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. Which of the following are purposes of cost accounting?  \n(I) To determine the cost of a product or service.  \n(II) To serve as a guide to price fixing.  \n(III) To provide information to shareholders on the profitability of a firm. \n(IV) To determine tax liabilities of firms.",
A: "I and II only",
B: "I and Ill only",
C: "I and Ill only",
D: "Ill and IV only",
answer: "A. I and II only",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. Which of the following is not an objective of cost accounting?",
A: "Control",
B: "Cost ascertainment",
C: "Planning",
D: "Revenue collection",
answer: "D. Revenue collection",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. Which of the following is a cost classification according to behaviour?",
A: "Fixed cost",
B: "Indirect cost",
C: "Factory cost",
D: "Production cost",
answer: "A. Fixed cost",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. Which of the following is a classification of cost based on relationship with a product?",
A: "Production cost",
B: "Direct cost",
C: "Variable cost",
D: "Distribution cost",
answer: "B. Direct cost",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. Which of the following is a prime cost?",
A: "Cost of detergents for cleaning factory machinery",
B: "Cost of grease for factory machinery",
C: "Wages of machine operator",
D: "Wages of factory cleaners",
answer: "C. Wages of machine operator",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Cost incurred even when there is no production is",
A: "conversion cost",
B: "differential cost",
C: "period cost",
D: "product cost",
answer: "C. Period cost",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Prime cost consists of direct materials, direct wages and",
A: "conversion cost",
B: "direct expenses",
C: "fixed cost",
D: "production overhead",
answer: "B. Direct expenses",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. The process of determining cost of products or services is",
A: "cost apportionment",
B: "cost ascertainment",
C: "cost classification",
D: "cost separation",
answer: "B. Cost ascertainment",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Which of the following is not a direct expense?",
A: "Carriage outwards",
B: "Cost of special design",
C: "Primary packaging material",
D: "Royalties",
answer: "A. Carriage outwards",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. Goods received Note is a document used in",
A: "Controlling stock.",
B: "identification stock",
C: "purchasing stock",
D: "stock valuation",
answer: "C. Purchasing stock",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Buffer stock is also referred to as",
A: "Maximum stock level",
B: "Minimum stock level",
C: "re-order level",
D: "re-order quantity",
answer: "B. Minimum stock level",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. Which of the following cannot be classified as material?",
A: "Consumable supplies",
B: "Loose tools",
C: "Plant and equipment",
D: "Raw materials",
answer: "C. Plant and equipment",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. What is the re-order level?",
A: "15,000 units",
B: "10,000 units",
C: "6,000 units",
D: "5,000 units",
answer: "B. 10,000 units",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. What is the maximum stock level?",
A: "18,000 units",
B: "16,000 units",
C: "15,000 units",
D: "14,000 units",
answer: "B. 16,000 units",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. What is the minimum stock level?",
A: "11,500 units",
B: "8,000, units",
C: "5,000 units",
D: "4,500 units",
answer: "B. 8,000 units",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. In Halsey Scheme, the proportion of time saved for which a worker gets bonus is",
A: "100%",
B: "50%",
C: "33 1/3%",
D: "25%",
answer: "B. 50%",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Idle time arises only when workers are paid on",
A: "bonus scheme basis",
B: "different piece work basis",
C: "straight piece rate basis",
D: "time rate-basis",
answer: "D. Time rate-basis",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. Wages sheet is prepared by",
A: "cost accounting department",
B: "payroll department",
C: "personnel department",
D: "time keeping department",
answer: "B. Payroll department",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. The method of paying employees based on quantity produced is",
A: "bonus scheme",
B: "overtime scheme",
C: "piece rate",
D: "time rate",
answer: "C. Piece rate",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. The predetermined overhead absorption rate is",
A: "Le 5.00 per unit",
B: "Le 4.44 per unit",
C: "4.00 per unit",
D: "Le 2.22 unit",
answer: "B. Le 4.44 per unit",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Overhead absorbed is",
A: "Le 62,500",
B: "Le 55,500",
C: "Le 50,000",
D: "Le 27,750",
answer: "B. Le 55,500",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. The overhead for the period is",
A: "Le 12,500 under-absorbed",
B: "Le 5,500 under-absorbed",
C: "Le 5,500 over absorbed",
D: "Le 12,500 over-absorbed",
answer: "C. Le 5,500 over-absorbed",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. The salary of a production manager is classified as",
A: "distribution overhead",
B: "factory overhead",
C: "selling overhead",
D: "variable overhead",
answer: "B. Factory overhead",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. Rent and rates are best apportioned by",
A: "floor area",
B: "horse power",
C: "metre reading",
D: "number of employees",
answer: "A. Floor area",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. Where premises used for production is owned, a charge in lieu in lieu of rent is",
A: "differential cost",
B: "notional cost",
C: "opportunity cost",
D: "sunk cost",
answer: "B. Notional cost",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. If costing profit is D 25,000, the profit as per financial account is",
A: "D33,000",
B: "D 31,000",
C: "D 27,000",
D: "D 25,000",
answer: "B. D 31,000",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. If financial profit is D 40,000; then profit as per cost account is",
A: "46,000",
B: "42,000",
C: "34,000",
D: "D 32,000",
answer: "C. D 34,000",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. Loss that is not anticipated under normal production conditions is",
A: "abnormal loss",
B: "bad debt",
C: "net loss",
D: "normal loss",
answer: "A. Abnormal loss",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. The costing method used by a business is determined by the",
A: "administrative procedure",
B: "materials used",
C: "nature of cost units",
D: "number of employees",
answer: "C. Nature of cost units",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. The difference between the value of work certified and the cost of work certified is",
A: "apparent profit",
B: "estimated profit",
C: "notional loss",
D: "work-in-progress",
answer: "A. Apparent profit",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Total variable cost increases when",
A: "fixed cost increases",
B: "production decrease",
C: "production increases",
D: "selling price increases",
answer: "C. Production increases",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. The practice of charging only variable cost to operations, processes or products is",
A: "absorption costing",
B: "marginal costing",
C: "output costing",
D: "standard costing",
answer: "B. Marginal costing",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. The difference between actual sales volume and break even point sales volume is",
A: "angle of incidence",
B: "break even analysis",
C: "C/S ratio",
D: "Margin of safety",
answer: "D. Margin of safety",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. What is the contribution per unit?",
A: "GH¢ 24",
B: "GH¢ 10",
C: "GH¢ 8",
D: "GH¢ 4",
answer: "C. GH¢ 8",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. What is the break even point in units?",
A: "6,400",
B: "2,700",
C: "1,600",
D: "1,500",
answer: "C. 1,600",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. What is the C/S ratio?",
A: "60%",
B: "80%",
C: "40%",
D: "10%",
answer: "A. 60%",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Which of the following is true of a cash budget?",
A: "It is a grant to a manager",
B: "It is prepared with an authorization from the bank",
C: "It is the company’s cash balance",
D: "It shows the expected cash shortage or surpluses",
answer: "D. It shows the expected cash shortage or surpluses",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. If the total budget expenditure for 17,000 units is GH¢ 58,000 and for 18,000 units is GH¢ 60,000, what is the estimated fixed cost?",
A: "GH¢ 24,000",
B: "GH¢ 12,000",
C: "GH¢ 2,000",
D: "GH¢ 1,000",
answer: "B. GH¢ 12,000",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Which of the following does not cause direct material usage variance?",
A: "Defective material",
B: "High material prices",
C: "Pilferage",
D: "Wastage",
answer: "B. High material prices",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Labour efficiency variance is calculated as",
A: "Standard hour (Standard rate-Actual rate)",
B: "Actual hour (Standard rate-Actual rate)",
C: "Actual rate (Standard hour -Actual hour)",
D: "Standard rate (Standard hour – Actual hour)",
answer: "D. Standard rate (Standard hour – Actual hour)",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},


]